hello my name is green and welcome back
to another episode of hermitcraft and as
you can see i've been working on this
lowest level i have tidied up quite a
lot because a lot of comments were
getting a bit annoyed with how messy i
was and you've got to remember guys that
this entire project this massive build
is going to be a work in progress for
like
months i don't know when i'm going to
finish so if there's something that's
particularly annoying you i can fix it
eventually but it's going to take time
so as you can see i've cleared out the
rest of this and i've got to say it does
look pretty cool it's not perfect yet i
have kind of tidied up this upper half
but
this is seriously where it's lacking at
the moment but as for this bottom half
from the middle downwards it looks
pretty cool i've got to admit and also
because i now have this beacon that i
spent everything i have on i actually
have started something else i started to
dig a big hole
i don't know why but i have started to
dig a very big hole because you never
know when you're gonna need a big hole
all of those chests are full of loads of
stuff it's pretty dangerous down here
i've got to admit but there's just
something so satisfying about
removing these blocks very quickly and
you'd be surprised how long it takes
even with the beacon this still takes a
really really long time i imagine that
there may even be a secret base
underneath here at some point i'm not
entirely sure but the big hole will
become useful i'm sure at some point but
for now what we're doing is working on
the upper base i keep moving on to the
next section of the build before i
finish the other so this looks pretty
good these towers have barely been
touched since i made them the first time
but you know around the corner i haven't
even done these pillars yet i haven't
finished all of these there's loads of
little things that are just taking a lot
of time to do but i'm gonna get there in
the end don't you worry but we have a
bit more of a pressing matter to discuss
that has nothing to do with the progress
on my blender or cake or building
whatever you want to call it this has
appeared i have no idea what this is so
we're just going to leave that for now
over the way there's been a bit of a
development that deeply deeply concerns
me this is the black pearl this belongs
to iskall and it sells prismarine and
sea lanterns and stuff but at the back
there's a rather hidden secret room
there's a little bit worrying
in here
there's this very odd scene going on and
it is
well
it's the black book
you see
this is where you can order a hit on
somebody the black book of the black
pearl you order a hit on a fellow hermit
simply enter the target and do not sign
and it costs 64 diamonds
to do that
so
i have been informed through various
means that somebody and that somebody
was jevin
put a hit
on me so what this means is
jevin in response to my afk prank on him
has gone and ordered a hit on me and
spent a lot of diamonds to do it
there is absolutely no chance of me
winning in a pvp battle no way not with
iskall iskall is
well for want of a better word a bit of
a pro at pvp there is no chance of me
being able to battle this one out so
we have a bit of a predicament but we
also have an advantage
jevin
actually wanted me to know
that this hit was coming
now this isn't iskal's fault iskall made
this shop and he's just following the
rules they're meant to be anonymous but
jevin made a mistake
we now know that this hit is on its way
okay we now know
that this is coming for us
so that means we have time to prepare
i have no idea iskals
this guy's online at the moment but he's
afk i don't even know if he knows about
the whole hit thing yet he might have
not checked the shop
but this gives us a major major
advantage
we can prepare
and i'm thinking what we're gonna do
is create a safe room with a little bit
of a trap in it so what we're gonna do
is when iskal comes after me we're gonna
make a safe room i'm gonna hide in there
and there's gonna be a trap that
hopefully
sends him on his way
anyway we should just get on with it i
think we don't have much time to dawdle
he could come at any second now
my current thinking is the safe room
should be somewhere around here because
here's my thinking right this is clearly
an area which i need to fix because it's
showing on the glass so it's not
out of the question that i would have
dug underneath here to try and fix it it
is also believable that there would be a
bunch of gravel here so what we do is we
make it look like we've been working
here and make it believable as possible
if we cover this in sand and gravel it
totally looks believable especially if i
break this and it falls through
this looks so realistic so i don't think
iskal would have any reason to suspect
any misgivings or trickery or anything
like that we're only trying to protect
ourselves i'm gonna run in
we're gonna i'm gonna run around this
corner and as he comes to get me i'm
gonna activate a trigger that's going to
completely remove all of these and he's
gonna fall
so we need to create
a big hole actually we need to create a
big hole down as far as we can the
mechanism is going to be very very
simple we're going to have five pistons
that are going to be extended
and over the top of them there is going
to be some sand or gravel so we got to
make this look believable if there's
sand and gravel already here and it
looks really messy
i can't see that he'll think anything of
it that looks pretty convincing with all
the water dripping maybe if we put a
crafting table here that really sets the
scene
and it would look like a pretty decent
place to go hiding especially if i ran
in here and then tried to cover it up
like that and then come down here he
would instantly follow me and then he
comes around the corner and i go
and he falls down
brilliant
now to really make sure
that this does the job because otherwise
he's just gonna come back for me and
back for me and back for me we need to
make sure that this kills iskall without
removing any of his stuff
and i think the best way to do that is
through simple fall damage i thought
about trying to suffocate him in sand
but i just don't think it's gonna cut it
so
i reckon
we should make some lava
just droop over the edge so if i place
signs all along here and then i place
lava
here
i just need a couple more buckets of
lava
and then we will have this whole thing
covered
but for now
we need to dig this hole all the way to
bedrock also while we're making this i
think it's a really really important
thing to point out that anything that
happens on hermitcraft
is for me to deal with okay if if
someone had done something to annoy me
then i would defend myself in that
situation okay it is definitely not the
place of you guys to go and defend me on
other people's channels it's really
really important to me that you guys be
constructive and positive i completely
understand why jevin put a hit on my
head i messed with him when he was afk
he didn't do anything to me i just
decided to mess with him it doesn't
matter that it failed or not it's just a
funny thing we're all having a load of
fun on hermitcraft and nobody actually
means any harm so i really really don't
want to see any toxic comments on
anybody's channel honestly and
definitely not iskal iskall doesn't know
what's gonna hit him i don't think
we're just really lucky that we got a
bit of a head start on this and we know
that it's coming because otherwise
i'm not sure we would have lived well i
know for a fact we wouldn't have lived
i'm already paranoid he might be on his
way to get me right now and i don't know
but if i'm not ready no chance i have no
chance
will the gravel just stop at the lava
because of the signs
ah
60 levels let's test it
not even close
i don't know maybe we should just stick
to the plan maybe maybe killing him is
not the best idea in the first place to
be honest maybe if we just trap him down
there and we say come on leave me alone
then that'll be enough i i doubt it i
still think we should stick with the
plan
i don't really want to kill anybody as
you know but this is self-defense this
is a panic room for sure i'm pretty sure
if i can do this it will work
brilliantly if i can give him a little
bit of a run around i run in here he'll
be following me i'll stop here just as
he comes around the corner and he's
about to go in he's about to kill me
if i just replace those pistons with
sticky pistons
it doesn't even make a difference
it's a good job we decided to test this
otherwise it could have gone horribly
horribly wrong
so we are officially set up
just place that in there
and bada bing bada boom we got ourselves
a system there's no gravel involved
whatsoever now so the fall should be
nice and clean
we officially
have ourselves a safe room for it when
we eventually get hit
oh boy
i can't see this ending well
i can't see it ending well for me and i
can't see it ending well for for anybody
and i don't blame jevin one little bit
because this was probably an easy way
for him to deal with my prankery
without without actually having anything
to do with me at all so kudos to you
jevin you may also notice that i named
my pickaxe the fax machine and are
wondering why well it's a fast pickaxe
machine so it's the fax machine simple
as that let's crack on with the rest of
the base building shall we i've still
got lots of little jobs to do especially
around these sorts of areas i'm still
wondering what exactly to do with each
layer here but
i've got a pretty decent idea for at
least one of them
[Music]
saved also i think it's a good idea that
we go and check on the skeleton horse
thing because i think i heard one of
them has been sold although i'm not sure
which one
let's see who won the little wager
and
oh would you look at that
it wasn't they call me t-bone it wasn't
skeletor
it was napoleon bonaparte that won
that means officially
32 diamonds to me for selling my
skeleton horse and you as all my witness
see that i am the only one that sold my
horse i don't know who bought it but
thank you so much
that means
this is my prize oh how brilliant i've
got the skeleton horse head and it's
probably the best mob head in the entire
game it doesn't really look like a horse
it looks like a a bear or something i
think it's so cool oh i'm so happy i got
this this i don't know what it's worth
but i uh well to be honest with you i
just wanted it because scar had it now
that i've got it it doesn't seem like
it's worth a lot but i'm gonna keep it
this is brilliant
hello
but that is a hefty 35 diamonds for
selling that horse not a bad little
profit but having said that that is it
the others need to sell their horses and
then this little stable will probably
have to come down because there's not
going to be many of these in stock
meanwhile we sold a few more gravel and
we sold a bit more sand and whenever i
put quartz in here it sells out really
quickly so i might restock that that
means i have officially
made
a shop and made a profit meaning i can
take that off of my bucket list which is
still in here i haven't actually been in
here for quite a while there's still
some resources here even if it's just a
little bit so my bucket list if you guys
don't remember this is a list of things
that i wanted to do this season feature
every hermit on the server at least once
well i've actually had a moment with
pretty much most of them i still haven't
had uh false or cleo or a few of the
other guys on yet but that i'm getting
there i've definitely
featured a lot of them start to shop and
make a profit i think we can officially
take that one off the list it is done
make a proper redstone storage system
not gonna happen
take mumbo's mustache away
hmm
i think this one
is gonna be what we work on next
create a base in every area long term
definitely not going to happen we can't
even finish the one that we've got
and kill a phantom while flying in
elytra well when they spawn i'm
definitely going to do that i feel like
i can at this point anyway i have a bit
of a plan here with my base let me let
me show you i'm thinking that these
towers need to go a lot taller but i
kind of noticed that this one i didn't
quite make it to the top and that gave
me an idea i'm thinking what we do is we
have it go up in increments so this one
stays where it is and then this one goes
a little bit higher and then that one
goes a little bit higher and then this
bit goes a bit so it kind of goes around
in a circle and every time you look
round it gets higher and higher and
higher until the three in the middle
will reach the top
which i think that's the build height
there so there's a pretty decent amount
of height to make these towers out of
and then i was thinking inside the
towers we have
we have ourselves an elevator in here
whoa
look how much damage i took from that i
thought that was a pretty swish landing
apparently not
apparently not i was also thinking it
might be an idea to have these towers
extend all the way through the base to
the very bottom but i haven't decided
whether i'm going to do that or not yet
so they might come down all the way
through here
and then it would mean you can come in
and then you can take the water elevator
up and then each tower could take you to
a different level so this tower could be
level one level two and level three the
only problem is one of the the tower
here
will come out here meaning i don't need
to even make one of these i don't know i
think it might work but it also might
ruin the vibe with the whole coral reef
thing these are this is the problem with
freestyling a build the way i am you
just don't really know there are so many
different options to take and i'm not
sure which way to go with it
building stuff like this isn't always an
exact science for example this side i've
just made it and i tried to make it
equidistant between each pillar but it's
not actually the same as this one
although you might not be able to tell
adding these towers in made it
incredibly difficult for me to keep
things even
right got to do the last one of these
pillars and then finally this is a job
that i've been putting off for way too
long
way too long
oh what was that
is this girl it's cisco it's this girl
invasive maneuvers invasive maneuvers
where is he rear view mirror
mirror
where is he
oh we got to do some skillful flying
here
double back double back double back
he doesn't have a clue
hold on let me get my bow where is he
no
ah are you i got hit
oh no no there's no way there's no way i
could do this okay oh wait let's say
from the safe room the safe room
he doesn't
i'm gonna have to give him the run
around i have to make it seem i have to
make it seem really legit i have to make
the scene legit i don't know where he's
gone right now maybe now's a good time
i can't see him
[Music]
i don't know where he's gone
these days there
does he know
no no no no no no
he went
oh my goodness
was he
oh my my little aching heart
my little aching heart oh my goodness it
worked
it worked i totally forgot
did you see him with the villager head
on him he is it at the moment he is
tagged oh my goodness he asked me to
bring his bring his stuff to him i'm
literally shaking my hands are shaking
oh i've never been so panicked in my
life
i said he said can he bring can i bring
his stuff to him i said yes as long as
he promises not to kill me
he said i'm sorry to him i'm sorry for
trying it's the life of a hitman that's
okay
that's okay
oh let's go and deliver this stuff to
him
look at that look at the state of his
stuff
unbreaking three infinity power five
flame punch one
super bow
oh my
look at the difference the escala
sharpness five look at all those
ah yeah i didn't stand a chance
i don't think that that's ever going to
work a second time right this is
iskall's base there he is i'm literally
shaking this gal like you scared the
life out of me but i can't believe that
man how how clever
like you knew about this didn't you well
yeah because every okay jevin is an
idiot okay what he did was he went to
your hitman shop and he told all of his
subscribers to inform me that you were
coming oh i was so sure i was gonna get
you there as well i was like
my goodness he's such a flyer but he's
stuck now and oh dude yeah well played
you deserve that there's your special
stuff now please is this it is that it
failed one is it one attempt kills all
is that it
yeah i guess so i mean i'd never really
plan to fail this to be honest but i
guess so
but i figured like he did order a hit
and i promised to not kill you so i'm
not going to kill you
i think i got all your stuff
but i can hit you right
no this is how it goes you have to do
that for a crew now
because technically he ordered a hit and
i just hit you so i i figure i'm you
know i
i have got it
i guess yeah i guess you can get paid by
jevin now so oh what's the deal here
have i got to wear all of this is this
why you died cause like listen i tested
out my trap several times and it didn't
kill me when i was like fully uh geared
up but you obviously didn't have all of
the gear because you had your elytra on
you had the dunce head and you had these
trousers
i may have survived if i used like if i
had fire protection trousers and my
normal gear but i've been stuck with
that with those yeah with those trousers
for a long time and no helmet
it was pretty rough it was pretty rough
so yeah now
there's so many stupid rules with tag
now why did i create this game
have you ever made the parkour have you
ever checked it it's so hard man it's so
tough oh of course i've got to go to the
tag building
yes oh yes you do i kind of feel like a
winner at the end of this anyway i felt
so bad after
i've totally lost i i know you're a
great guy but i didn't see that
level of craftsmanship coming that was
well
played
i feel like we both we've both won and
we've both lost here yeah i i at least i
lost the villager head and the stupid
trousers so i'm happy about that that's
really really gonna be put on now i
think it's such a giveaway as well if
you see oh of course i've got to put it
on oh no this is such a dead giveaway if
you see anybody with this head no one's
going to want to talk to me
this is like
this is like the anti-hermit my advice
though please please hit ren
run run dog well i i guess we're we're
even we're square no hard feelings no
hard feelings no hard feelings at all
and
jevin i think you got what you wanted
and we're square on the afk front so i
think between the three of us
no more fighting we're done this is over
we're fighting this is it we've done it
that's it game over
well i better head over to the tag
building now
yeah have fun with that let me know as
well how long your parkour took because
for me it took an hour and 20 minutes
an hour and 20 an hour and 20 minutes i
don't like parkour oh my goodness okay
all right
cheers see ya
oh
well that kind of worked out in the end
i guess
oh my goodness i can't believe we're it
again
so there's a whole bunch of rules and
stuff i kind of went over it when i
where is the tag building i don't
remember exactly where but there's a
whole bunch of rules that we have to do
we have to do a parkour ah here it is
here's the tag tower well
i am a i'm a victim of my own creation
it would seem wait a minute
oh my goodness it's like history
is mumbo tagging me with the how many
times am i going to appear in this now
oh my goodness
there's cub getting a potion on oh wow
this is oh this is brilliant this is
like a whole interactive history i love
this i'm loving this right so i'm tagged
again this is like my third time we have
to take the walk of shame this was my
own idea
oh
shame
oh come on
stupid thing what is it filling me up
with at the moment no one wants to be
tagged hang your head dunce i will hang
my head what was that
slow uh made me slow brilliant okay now
we got to do the parkour
yep
yep so iskall said this took him an hour
and a half
i can see it oh no
really
do i have to jump on there
that can't be right oh no i got a double
back
ah
this is the worst punishment that has
ever been devised by man this parkour is
poorly designed not because it's
infuriating but because you can hit your
head any parkour maker knows that you
don't create jumps where you can hit
your head
we've got to check our head every time
now
there we go now where do i go
where do i go from here
oh all the way over there
oh here we go
and in the corner
okay
we're getting somewhere we're getting
somewhere
oh
yes
oh what an awful jump
what an awful jump we're so close we're
so close
yes
oh my goodness
who don't fail legs don't fail me now
i wasn't ready for this oh my goodness
oh my goodness
yes
oh my goodness we made it
okay
that only took me about five minutes in
the end it did take a lot of
oh
from that one alone getting over
that uh you know enough no more
never again congratulations now take
that leap of faith thank goodness for
that
well it's finished now
i did help briefly make this enter the
rules chamber
the rules of tag please read the book
before heading to the next room
all right
rid yourself of the shame and burden you
must tag another hermit please read and
understand all of the rules i pretty
sure i know the rules before tagging
another player you must wait until yours
and their perspectives have been posted
you cannot tag another player in the
same episode you were tagged
you must keep the tag and dunce head in
your inventory at all times until you
tag a player to tag a player approach
them and slap them with the tag you are
now it yeah yada yada yada you cannot
tag afk you cannot tag the last person
that tagged you yada yada each round has
a twist head into the next room and
press the button to receive a random
twist
you may also add your own twist into the
randomizer best of luck
great
get your twist
give green a diamond give green a
diamond block
no way
do you think i should take another one
i feel like i don't know
there's no point cause nothing changes i
feel like i should put this back
i should get another twist
you can't use rockets when tagging
so no flying at all that's gonna make it
so difficult to approach someone as i
can't chase anybody down if i can't use
rockets all right let's add a twist in
here
okay i think i got a good one
i'm gonna add you've got a 360 no scope
your next tag that could be entertaining
oh i can't i should have just kept the
one that said give green a diamond block
i just didn't feel like it it didn't
feel right because obviously nothing
would change i'd have to give myself a
diamond block so yeah i've got a real
i've got a real twist in here now
the current twist if the tag trousers
break you must sell seven iou notes for
seven diamonds in each shop area where
the tag trousers when at all times the
dunce head you can remove the dunce head
from the game by adding curse of binding
and equipping it on another hermit you
must wear the tag trousers at all times
when tagged it doesn't say that about
the dunce head though
you can remove it by adding cursive
binding and giving it to another hermit
does that i don't know if that's even
separate from
everything else
hmm that's all have fun
great
do i have to add my name to the list of
history now hey look there's me that's
the first one i did then mumbo
and then doc and then i guess this is
the the sort of the hall of history so
that was me first then i tagged mumbo
who tagged oh wait or did i attack no
wait i tagged doc then he tagged mumbo
oh whatever
this is so cool the tag has become
increasingly more
prevalent oh i love this so much except
i don't love it i don't really want to
be a dunce
i think that's i'm never gonna get used
to this head i think that's probably
enough for today's episode
things didn't really go to plan in the
end did they thank you very much for
watching and please let me know in the
comments as a matter of urgency who you
think should get tagged next and i
preferably want to tag someone that has
not been tagged yet which does include
ren who iskal asked me to tag but there
are others as well i am not set on any
one person it is an opportunistic thing
okay thanks everyone and goodbye